RG 068, Film and Video
Connecticut State Library
Film and video collection
1919-1992
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut State Library (collector)
9.5 cubic feet
RG068
Multiple
Scope and Content
Provenance
In 1938, Commissioner of Aeronautics Charles L. Morris deposited two original reels, titled Flight which were made in 1933, with the Connecticut State Library in exchange for copies. Morris also deposited a script he had written and was revised up to April 1, 1938.
Governor Wilbur Cross Meets with His Cabinet for the Last Time was deposited in the Connecticut State Library in January 1939.
Connecticut Answers was acquired by the Connecticut State Library either on November 30, 1945 or January 10, 1946.
Editorials: Connecicut Constitution was acquired by the Connecticut State Library in 1966.
Governor Raymond E. Baldwin, Jr. Reviews the Accomplishments of His Administration was acquired by the Connecticut State Library in 1941.
American Heritage was acquired by the Connecticut State Library in June 1957.
Tobacco Valley: The Story of Shade Grown Tobacco was acquired by the Connecticut State Library in 1972.
Connecticut Constitutional Convention 1965 was acquired by the Connecticut State Library in 1966.
Governor Baldwin of Connecticut was acquired by the Connecticut State Library in 1984.
WICC-TV in Bridgeport sent the reel of Governor John Lodge to the state capitol in 1954. It was acquired by the Connecticut State Library in 1989.
In Memorium: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tapes #1-6 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) were acquired by the Connecticut State Library on April 29, 1981.
Connecticut-Something Old-Something New by Joseph A. Fiorelli was acquired by the Connecticut State Library on September 2, 2010.
Container List
- Inventory, 1919-1992
  - T003300
    - Bill of Rights TV Commercials [videorecording]. Philip Morris, undated; 1 videocassette (VHS): 4 min., 15 sec., 1/2 in. (Box 1)
    - Constitution Plaques Presentation [videorecording]. Strong Arts Inc, 1989 July 17; 1 videocassette (VHS): 5 min., 46 sec., 1/2 in. (Box 1)
    - Ratifcation Convention [videorecording], 1988 January 9; 1 videocassette (VHS, slow speed): 4 min., 15 sec., 1/2 in. (Box 1)
    - Constitutional Symposium #1 [videorecording], undated; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 1)
    - Constitutional Symposium #2 [videorecording], undated; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 1)
    - President L.B. Johnson Address During Gov. Dempsey Campaign [videorecording]. The Connecticut Network (CTN), undated; 1 videocassette (VHS): 2 hr., 40 min., 1/2 in. (Box 1)
      Looped film transfer.
    - Flight [film], 1933; 1 reel, 9 in., silent, b & w, 16mm (Box 1 rc)
    - Flight (Reels 1 & 2) [videorecording], 1933; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP L): silent, b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 5 rc)
      Transferred from 16mm in August 2001.
    - Flight (Reels 1 & 2) [videorecording], 1933; 2 videocassette copies (VHS): silent, b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 1)
      2 copies of a paper script of film are with the videocassette.
      Transfered from Beta SP master in August 2001 from Northeast Historic Film.
    - Flight (Reels 1 & 2) [videorecording], 1933; 2 videocassette copies (VHS): silent, b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 5)
    - Governor Raymond E. Baldwin, Jr. Reviews the Accomplishments of His Administration [film], 1941 January 7; 1 reel, 8 in., sd., b & w, 16mm (Box 2rc)
      January 7th was the day before the inauguration of Baldwin's successor, Robert Hurley.
      May also include remarks by unidentified state officials.
    - Governor Raymond E. Baldwin, Jr. Reviews the Accomplishments of His Administration [videorecording], 1941 January 7; 4 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 5)
    - CSL Flood - News Coverage [videorecording], 1989 December 2; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 1)
      RG 12, 91-25 is written on the videocassette case.
    - We the People - A staged reading at Christ Episcopal Church, Stratford, Conn. [videorecording]. Books & lyrics by Steven Otfinoski. Music by Richard Amend & Mary Lang, 1987 September 17; 1 videocassette (VHS SP): mono, 1/2 in. (Box 1)
      Videocassette is in large envelope with correspondence and projected budget for school touring company of "We the People" from Steven Otfinoski to Janet Crook, Executive Director, U.S. Constitution Bicentennial Commission of Connecticut, 10/28/1987.
    - African and Native American Medicine in Early New England [videorecording]. History Day Contest Fox Middle School, Hartford Conn., 1992; 1 videocassette (VHS): 2nd ed., 1/2 in. (Box 1)
      Videocassette is in large envelope with paper report of how the film was made and list of works used.
    - A Grand Restoration [videorecording], undated; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 1)
      Post-it note on videocassette case reads: "Received from MB on 7/3/1990. Get deed form to CPTV. They will want to retain copyright. MJ 7/3/1990."
    - General Assembly [videorecording]. CPTV, 1988 April 28; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 1)
    - 3 CT Car III [videorecording]. Babbidge, undated; 1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. (Box 1)
    - New York World's Fair [film], 1940; 1 film roll, col., 35mm (Box 1)
    - 1965 Constitutional Convention [videorecording]. NY, Boston series, 1992 January 9; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 2)
    - Hartford Circus Fire: Her Name is Eleanor [videorecording]. WFSB-TV, Hartford, Conn., undated; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 2)
      In envelope titled accession 91-044.
    - Circus Fire Investigation: March 8-12, 1991 [videorecording]. WFSB-TV, Hartford, Conn., undated; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 2)
      In envelope titled accession 91-044 with deed of gift and correspondence regarding the two videos fo the Hartford Circus Fire from WFSB-TV. Pencil note on video reads: "RG 69:105, not for copying."
    - Reception and Proceedings on the Renaming of the Museum, Memorial Hall (Baldwin Reception) [videorecording], 1938 January 20; 1 videocassette (U-matic): col., 3/4 in. (Box 2)
    - Constitution Signers Series Part 1 [videorecording]. United States Army, 1987; 1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. (Box 2)
    - Sikorsky Exhibit at the State Library [videorecording]. P.M. Magazine Ch. 3, 1982 March 18; 1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. (Box 2)
    - Homer Babbidge-Reflections [videorecording], 1984 April 9; 1 videocassette (U-matic): 58 min., 49 sec., 3/4 in. (Box 2)
    - General Assembly [videorecording], 1988 April 29; 1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. (Box 2)
    - The Connecticut State Library - What's It All About? [videorecording], circa 1984; 1 videocassette (U-matic): col., 4 min., 44 sec., 3/4 in. (Box 2)
    - We The People - A Bicentennial Celebration [videorecording], undated; 1 videocassette (U-matic): 19 min., 48 sec., 3/4 in. (Box 2)
    - A Bicentennial Celebration - We The People [videorecording]. United States Army, 1987 June 16; 1 videocassette (U-matic): 60 min., 3/4 in. (Box 2)
      Enclosed in the videocassette case are papers regarding the contents of the videocassette and a list in sequence of constitutional signers that appear on the videocassette.
    - Presidents [videorecording]; The 26th Amendment [videorecording]; Don't Forget [videorecording]; Don't Forget (News Show) [videorecording]. The Advertising Council/U.S. Constitution, 1987 February 18; 1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. (Box 2)
    - State Supreme Court Coverage - 1st Day of 1 Year Experiement With Allowing Cameras in the Courtroom [videorecording]. WVIT-TV Channel 30, Hartford, Conn.; WFSB-TV Channel 3, Hartford, Conn., 1982 June 1; 1 videocassette (U-matic): col., 3/4 in. (Box 2)
    - Connecticut Constitutional Convention 1965 [film], 1 reel, 11.5 in., sd., b & w, 16mm (Box 1rc)
      Segments shot by WHNB-TV in New Britain of the convention itself and activities leading up to the convention. Script sequence and sequence on film are not synchronized.
      Transferred to VHS by CPTV in 1988.
    - Connecticut Constitutional Convention 1965 [videorecording], 1 videocassette (Betacam SP L): sd., b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
    - Connecticut Constitutional Convention 1965 [videorecording], 1 videocassette (VHS): sd., b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 3)
      Transferred from 16mm film.
    - Editorials: Connecticut Constitution [film], 1965 December; 1 reel, 4 in., sd., b & w, 16mm (Box 2rc)
      Made by WNHC-TV Film Department, New Haven and contains two 60 second editorials read by WNHC station manager. One editorial urges viewers to vote yes on Proposal 1, giving greater regpresentation in the State Senate. The other editorial pertains to eminent doamin compensation. Description of contents are from CPTV which viewed the film.
    - Editorials: Connecticut Constitution [videorecording], 1965 December; 1 videocassette (VHS): sd., b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 3)
    - Editorials: Connecticut Constitution [videorecording], 1965 December; 2 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 4)
    - Governor John Dempsey Gubernatorial Campaign of 1966 Film #1 [film], circa 1964-1965; 1 reel, 9.5 in., 16mm (Box 1rc)
    - Governor John Dempsey Gubernatorial Campaign of 1966 Film #1 [videorecording], circa 1964-1965; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP S): 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
      Transferred from 16mm in September 2001.
    - Governor John Dempsey Gubernatorial Campaign of 1966 Film #1 [videorecording], circa 1964-1965; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 3)
    - Governor John Dempsey Gubernatorial Campaign of 1966 Film #2 [film], circa 1966; 1 reel, 8.75 in., 16mm (Box 1rc)
    - Governor John Dempsey Gubernatorial Campaign of 1966 Film #2 [videorecording], circa 1966; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP S): 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
    - Governor John Dempsey Gubernatorial Campaign of 1966 Film #2 [videorecording], circa 1966; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 3)
    - Governor John Dempsey Gubernatorial Campaign of 1966 Film #3 [film], circa 1966; 1 reel, 6.5 in., 16mm (Box 2rc)
    - Governor John Dempsey Gubernatorial Campaign of 1966 Film #3 [videorecording], circa 1966; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 3)
    - Mansfield Training School: Chicago Special Olympics [film], 1968; 1 reel, 10.25 in., 16mm (Box 1rc)
    - Mansfield Training School: Chicago Special Olympics [videorecording], 1968; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 3)
    - Mansfield Training School: 50th Anniversary Parade [film], 1967; 1 reel, 9.75 in., 16mm (Box 1rc)
    - Mansfield Training School: 50th Anniversary Parade [videorecording], 1967; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 3)
    - Mansfield Training School: Chicago Olympics; 50th Anniversary Parade [videorecording], 1967-1968; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP L): 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
    - Mansfield Training School: 4th of July Parade [film], 1968; 1 reel, 6.25 in., 16mm (Box 2rc)
    - Mansfield Training School: 4th of July Parade [videorecording], 1968; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 3)
    - Mansfield Training School: Mrs. Kelly Parades [film], 1967-1968; 1 reel, 8 in., 16mm (Box 1rc)
    - Mansfield Training School: Mrs. Kelly Parades [videorecording], 1967-1968; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 3)
    - Mansfield Training School: Mrs. Kelly Parades; 4th of July Parade [videorecording], 1967-1968; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP S): 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
    - Governor John Lodge [film], 1952; 1 reel, 4 in., b & w, 16mm (Box 2rc)
    - Governor John Lodge [videorecording], 1952; 4 videocassette copies (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 4)
    - Governor John Lodge; Editorials: CT Constitutional Convention; Governor John Dempsey Campaign Film #3 [videorecording], 1952, circa 1965-1966; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP S): 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
    - Governor Baldwin of Connecticut (Reel 1) [film], circa 1941; 1 reel, 6.5 in., 16mm (Box 2rc)
      Developed by Worcester Film Corp., Worcester, MA.
    - Governor Baldwin of Connecticut (Reel 2) [film], circa 1941; 1 reel, 5.75 in., 16mm (Box 2rc)
    - Governor Baldwin of Connecticut (Reels 1 & 2) [videorecording], circa 1941; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP S): 1/2 in. (Box 5rc)
      Transferred from 16mm in August 2001 by Northeast Historic Film.
    - Governor Baldwin of Connecticut (Reels 1 & 2) [videorecording], circa 1941; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 5)
    - Governor Wilbur Cross Meets with His Cabinet for the Last Time [film], 1938 December 9; 1 reel, 6.25 in., sd., b & w, 16mm (Box 2 rc)
      Governor Cross reads the 1938 Thanksgiving Proclamation and reviews accomplishments of his administration.
    - Governor Wilbur Cross Meets with His Cabinet for the Last Time [videorecording], 1938 December 9; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP S): sd., b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 5 rc)
    - Governor Wilbur Cross Meets with His Cabinet for the Last Time [videorecording], 1938 December 9; 4 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 5)
    - Victory Celebration in Litchfield, Conn. [videorecording], 1919 July 4; 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. (Box 5)
      Transfered by Northeast Historic Film.
    - Connecticut Answers [film], circa 1945; 1 reel, 8 in., sd., b & w, 16mm (Box 2rc)
      Film made by SNET and narrated by Lowell Thomas. Includes great images of Connecticut industry in World War II.
      Transferred to VHS by CPTV in November 1991.
    - Connecticut Answers [videorecording], circa 1945; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., b & w, 1/2 in. (Box 5)
      Transferred from Beta SP master in August 2001 from Northeast Historic Film.
    - American Heritage [film], 1957 March 7; 1 reel, 7.5 in., sd., b & w, 16mm, 13 min., 30 sec. (Box 2rc)
      Documents the transfer of Colt Museum to the State of Connecticut in 1957 by the Penn-Texas Co. Includes also segments on Samuel Colt, the inside at the factory, and the transfer ceremony in Memorial Hall, Connecticut State Library Building on March 7, 1957.
      This is one of 5 prints that were made. Transferred to VHS by CPTV in 1991.
    - American Heritage [videorecording], 1957 March 7; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP S): sd., b & w, 1/2 in., 13 min., 30 sec. (Box 5rc)
    - American Heritage [videorecording], 1957 March 7; 4 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., b & w, 1/2 in., 13 min., 30 sec. (Box 5)
    - Tobacco Valley: The Story of Shade Grown Tobacco [film], circa 1940s; 1 reel, 10.5 in., sd., col., 16mm (Box 1rc)
      Narrated by Lowell Thomas. Produced by the Shade Tobacco Growers Agricultural Association in Windsor, CT. which no longer exists.
      Transferred to VHS by CPTV in 1991.
    - Tobacco Valley: The Story of Shade Grown Tobacco [videorecording], circa 1940s; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP L): sd., col., 1/2 in. (Box 5rc)
    - Tobacco Valley: The Story of Shade Grown Tobacco [videorecording], circa 1940s; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., col., 1/2 in. (Box 5)
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #1 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording]. WVIT-TV channel 30, Hartford, Conn., 1981 February 6; 1 videocassette (U-matic): sd., 3/4 in. (Box 3rc)
      Made by WVIT-TV, Channel 30, Hartford 6 p.m news.
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #2 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording]. WVIT-TV channel 30, Hartford, Conn., 1981 February 8; 1 videocassette (U-matic): sd., 3/4 in. (Box 3rc)
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #3 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording]. WVIT-TV channel 30, Hartford, Conn., 1981 February 8; 1 videocassette (U-matic): sd., 3/4 in. (Box 3rc)
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #4 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording]. WVIT-TV channel 30, Hartford, Conn., 1981 February 9; 1 videocassette (U-matic): sd., 3/4 in. (Box 3rc)
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #5 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording]. WVIT-TV channel 30, Hartford, Conn., 1981 February 8; 1 videocassette (U-matic): sd., 3/4 in. (Box 3rc)
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #6 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording]. WVIT-TV channel 30, Hartford, Conn., 1981 February 9; 1 videocassette (U-matic): sd., 3/4 in. (Box 3rc)
    - In Memorium: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #1 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 6; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP L): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
      Transferred from 3/4 in. master in September 2001.
    - In Memorium: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #2 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 8; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP L): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
    - In Memorium: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #3 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 8; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP L): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
    - In Memorium: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #4 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 9; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP L): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
    - In Memorium: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #5 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 8; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP L): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
    - In Memorium: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #6 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 9; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP L): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4rc)
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #1 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 6; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4)
      Transferred from 3/4 in. master by Northeast Historic Film.
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #2 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 8; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4)
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #3 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 8; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4)
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #4 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 9; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4)
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #5 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 8; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4)
    - In Memoriam: Governor Ella T. Grasso Tape #6 (Connecticut Mourns the Death of Governor Ella T. Grasso) [videorecording], 1981 February 9; 3 videocassette copies (VHS): sd., 1/2 in. (Box 4)
  - On the Road: '76 Conn. [film]. CBS News, undated; 1984-009B; 1 reel, 5 in., 16mm (Box Shared hollinger)
  - Connecticut-Something Old-Something New [film]. Joseph A. Fiorelli, 1967; 2011-020; 1 reel + supplemental material, 10.5 in., sd., col., 16mm (Box 3rc)
    Supplemental material includes the original certificate of honors for the film from the Connecticut Educational Film Library Association (EFLA) in 1968; the original black and white proof sheets for the film; copy of certificate of participation awarded to Fiorelli Films, Inc. for the film Micralign 140 by the Connecticut Film Festival on November 18, 1978; and Joseph A. Fiorelli's dossier listing credentials and awards with a photograph of the film maker.
  - Connecticut State Veterans' Home & Hospital 125th Anniversary, 1989; 2011-124; 1 videocassette + 1 dvd